A Guide to the Gordon and Webster Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
- Series II: William Webster
  - 1972 Correspondence: Letters of sympathy for William Webster's death, 116 items (Box-folder 14:4)
    Some correspondents include Bob Brandt; Patricia McGrath Nash; Ogden E. Sawyer; Don Allen; Harold and Mary Morris; Sydney Baltzer Dodds; Edward Morehouse; Herbert Scoville; Manson Benedict; Julius Adams Stratton; Carroll L. Wilson; Richard Helms, Director of Central Intelligence who wrote "Bill gave this Agency a great deal of his talent and time over many years;" John O. Pastore; Raymond A. Gibson; Harry W. Wilcott; Sybil Shugg; Robert and Florence Spraque; James R. Schlesinger, Atomic Energy Commission; James T. Ramey; L. Ralston Thomas; Dudley W. Orr; George and Margaret Stoddard; Vince A. Fulmer, Vice President of Massachusetts Institute of Technology; Omond M. Solandt; Jerry Tape; Norman F. Ramsey; Robert L. Wells; Paul M. Fye; Edwin L. Goldwasser; James A. Perkins; Howard Vesper; J. R. Goldstein, Rand Corporation; Clyde Williams; Roger E. Batzel; Mrs. J. R. Killian; S. J. Buchsbaum; Duane C. Sewell; Avis K. Bellows; Stephen P. Jeffries; Andrew Onderdonk; Caroline Covent; Mrs. Sherman R. Knapp; Claiborne Pell, United States Senate; Jack E. Corette; Edward A. Mason; John H. Kane; Albert A. Cree; Thomas C. Desmond; Herman Kahn; Robert E. Quinn, United States Court of Military Appeals; Hallie Begg; Elsie Hoffman; Florence Mancuso; Cieb and Irwin L. Moore; Mrs. Leeds Armstrong Wheller; Kay Moore; Robert F. Bacher; Mrs. D. E. Mosely; Tina Anderson; Louisa Fletcher; Esther Von; Greta Brandt; Laura Lejeune; Mildred Sugden; Don Vandenburgh; Albert and Nancy Wheelon; Mrs. Alton Wilson Barstow; Charles Allen Thomas; W. H. Prentice, General Electric; Bill Bell; Helen and Ed Russo; Rosemary Tomei; Lillian Pulling; Martin A. O'Malley; Mrs. henry Gerald Carroll; Walter and Edna LoShots; Kay Foley; Ruth Robbins Green; Mrs. C. Joseph Gooch; Anne and Mac Hall; W. M. Hall; Jane Hall; Jacqueline O'Reilly; David A. Shepard; Herbert M. Johnson; Richard Wilson; Pat and Jim Sterner; Doris and Howard Cole; William T. Brightman, Jr.; Marge McGuiness; and Roger J. Coe, Vice President of Yankee Atomic Electric Company
  - 1972 May 17 Death of William Webster, 13 items (Box-folder 14:5)
    Included are obituaries and resolutions commending the life of William Webster.
  - 1962 William Webster: Eleanore's car accident and lawsuit, 32 items (Box-folder 14:6)
    William Webster's wife, Eleanore was killed instantly while driving their automobile in North Carolina. There are news clippings about the fatal accident and letters from attorneys about lawsuits against the Webster estate by the families, Doyle and Bellflower who also lost family members in the accident. There are also medical reports; notes made by William Webster and his diagrams of the accident.
  - 1962 William Webster: Eleanore's car accident and depositions, 2 items (Box-folder 14:7)
  - 19901998 Estate of Stevenson Williams Webster, 40 items (Box-folder 14:8)
    There is a will; requests for funeral arrangements; a biography of Stevenson Williams Webster by Harry Webster; and an application to the Massachusetts Society of Colonial Wars. There is also information to his beneficiaries about many stocks that he owned, such as Duke Power Company, New England Electric Systems, Rockwell International Corporation, Bell Atlantic; and various contributions and pledges.
  - 194219491972 William Webster: Financial, 9 items (Box-folder 14:9)
    There is an income tax return for 1942 and itemized list of the costs of William Webster's possessions after his death in 1972. There are also notes by William Webster and insurance and travel forms. According to the tax return, William Webster was making almost eighteen thousand dollars per year in 1942.
  - 1870-1973 William Webster: Genealogy: Judge Stevenson Archer Williams, 38 items (Box-folder 14:10)
    There is a letter from Stevenson Archer Williams, (1851-1932) a famous Maryland judge and attorney and William Webster's grandfather. He wrote to William Webster about his relations with the Squibb family. There are biographical notes on the judge's life; an invitation for a testimonial dinner in honor of his eightieth birthday; correspondence about his portrait for the court house; and a typed autograph file of letters by his Princeton classmates. (1870) There are also photocopies of news clippings about the testimonial dinner; death notices, and other news clippings including an obituary of Edwin H. Webster and articles about Bel Air, Maryland.
  - 1943 William Webster: Genealogy: Son of Lewis J. Williams, 3 items (Box-folder 14:11)
    Stevenson Archer Williams was a descendant of the well known Judge Stevenson Archer Williams mentioned above (1851-1932). He was the son of Lewis J. Williams and was killed when flying over the Gulf of Mexico during World War II. There is a telegram, a letter from William Webster's mother, and news clippings about the crash.
  - n. d. William Webster miscellaneous, 7 items (Box-folder 15:1)
    There are notes on the constellations; a list of favorite expressions; and travel brochures.
  - 1919-19281958 William Webster United States Navy, 29 items (Box-folder 15:2)
    There is printed information on "The Cruiser;" merit roll for a class of 1920; Directory of the Members of the Association of the Class of 1921; Petty Officer's Appointment; tax form for 1925; reporting orders; list of members of the Society of Naval Architects and Marine Engineers; requests for leave of absences; and his resignation letter.
  - 1961 William Webster News clippings Eleanore, 8 items (Box-folder 15:3)
  - n. d. William Webster Miscellaneous news clippings, 1 item (Box-folder 15:4)
  - 1946-1972 William Webster News clippings, 71 items (Box-folder 15:5)
    Included with news clippings about William Webster and atomic power is an article about Robert Oppenheimer.
  - 1942-1945 William Webster Personnel Tests, 6 items (Box-folder 15:6)
    There are intelligence and personality tests taken by William Webster.
  - n. d. William Webster Photographs Research and Development, 24 items (Box-folder 15:7)
    There are photographs of William Webster and his colleagues; an Archie Alexander photograph signed for William Webster. There are unidentified photographs of men in business, government and the Navy.
  - 19621998 William Webster Resume, 8 items (Box-folder 15:8)
    There are resumes and biographical information about William Webster including a report about him by his great granddaughter, Sarah Nemiah Ladd
  - 1959 William Webster Retirement Planning, 10 items (Box-folder 15:9)
    There are handwritten notes by William Webster outlining his retirement plans.
  - n. d. William Webster Speeches, 1 item (Box-folder 15:10)
    There is a Commencement address by William Webster to Bryant College.
  - 1946 Stevenson Williams Webster Thesis on Edith Wharton, 1 item (Box-folder 15:11)
    Steve Websters' Thesis from the University of Virginia, "The American Scene in the Novels of Edith Wharton"
  - 196119631972 William Webster: Truman Library (National Archives and Records Service), 7 items (Box-folder 15:12)
    There is correspondence between NARA and Mr. and Mrs. Webster about the placement of his papers.
- Series III: Ann Gordon Webster (Box-folder 15:13-23:11)
  - 1938-1940 Summers Correspondence Ann Gordon and her parents, 62 items (Box-folder 15:13)
    Ann and her parents corresponded while she was away for the summers at Camp Allegheny in Greenbrier County, West Virginia (1938-1939) and Camp Cherrilomac, in Cowart Northumberland County, Virginia (1940). Included are letters from Aunt Mary, (Mary Daniels Gordon, sister of Armistead Churchill Gordon, Jr.) her grandmother Mrs. J. N. Waddell, her best friend, Margaret ("Peggy," "Piglet") R. MacLeod, and a tent counselor report for Ann.
  - 1942 Correspondence Ann Gordon and her parents, 15 items (Box-folder 15:14)
    Ann and her parents corresponded while Ann was boarding at St. Anne's Belfield School and her parents were in Washington D. C. during the war. Armistead was a Lieutenant Commander in Army Intelligence and his wife Cornelia worked as an air drill warden and housemother for Waves.
  - 1943 January-May Correspondence Ann Gordon and her parents, 43 items (Box-folder 15:15)
    Also included are letters from her Aunt Mary (Mary Daniels Gordon, sister of Armistead Churchill Gordon, Jr.).
  - 1943 September-December Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 26 items (Box-folder 16:1)
    Ann Gordon and her parents corresponded while Ann was at St. Anne's Belfield School and her parents were in Washington D. C. during the war.
  - 1944 Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 53 items (Box-folder 16:2)
    Included are letters from Aunt Mary (Mary Daniels Gordon) who had moved to Ridgeway Farm in Charlottesville, Virginia.
  - 1945 Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 28 items (Box-folder 16:3)
    Ann's last year at St. Anne's and her parents were preparing to move back to Charlottesville.
  - 1946 Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 13 items (Box-folder 16:4)
    Ann and her parents corresponded while she was at Wellesley College. Armistead mentioned Rufus Jones and praised his sermons.
  - 1947 January-April Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 12 items (Box-folder 16:5)
    Armistead mentioned that the University Faculty petitioned the Board of Visitors for salary increases to meet the cost of living. He also commented that President Colgate Darden was likely to curtail the fraternity parties.
  - 1947 May-September Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 12 items (Box-folder 16:6)
  - 1947 October-December Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 17 items (Box-folder 16:7)
    Included are news clippings from Cornelia Gordon (Ann's mother).
  - 1948 Correspondence Ann Gordon with her parents, 36 items (Box-folder 16:8)
    Also included is correspondence between Cornelia and Armistead while he was in Washington, D.C.
  - 1949 June-September Correspondence Ann Gordon Webster and her parents, 24 items (Box-folder 17:1)
    Ann Gordon married Richard Henry Webster ("Harry," "R. H.," "Tig") on September 9 th, while she was in her last year of college at Wellesley. Letters are from Ann, Harry, and both sets of parents, William and Eleanore Webster and Armistead and Cornelia Gordon.
  - 1949 October-December Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 30 items (Box-folder 17:2)
    There are no letters from Ann's father in this time period,although there are comments from him in her mother's letters. Her father did write his own letters to Ann and they are currently in the possession of Ann Gordon's daughter. There is a news clippings about the death of football player Gene Edmunds.
  - 1950 January-April Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 47 items (Box-folder 17:3)
  - 1950 May-July Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 29 items (Box-folder 17:4)
    Cornelia's letters to Ann from 1950 to 1969 describe UVA faculty members and her daily life along with advice for Ann on every subject. She often enclosed news clippings of local events and advertisements of women's and men's fashions and household needs of the day. Cornelia mentioned the Korean War and wanted Harry to apply for officers training so that he would not get drafted. She also mentioned that Al Balz and Buzzie Chamberlain had been called up and she hoped that Armistead would not be called for Navy reserve. Cornelia also wrote that they were very upset that Frank Geldard had a heart attack.
  - 1950 August-December Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 26 items (Box-folder 17:5)
    Cornelia wrote that Ed Chamberlain had a bad heart and was not well. There are news clippings about Dr. Philip Hench, brother of Atcheson Hench, who was awarded the Nobel Prize in medicine and Atcheson Hench receiving an honorary degree at Lafayette College.
  - 1951 January-May Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 16 items (Box-folder 17:6)
    Armistead was writing the preface to a memorial volume for James Southall Wilson's retirement and he made a note to Ann that it was "the hardest thing I've ever tried to write." He also mentioned a dinner at Keswick for James Southall Wilson and that Clifton Waller Barrett spoke at the McGregor room. Ann and Harry had their first child, a son, William Webster III ("Barney").
  - 1951 June-December Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 30 items (Box-folder 18:1)
    Cornelia wrote that James Kindred had a heart attack. She also wrote about her concerns regarding the Korean War; and mentioned that Armistead had aged. Ann and Harry were preparing to go to Madrid, Spain.
  - 1953 Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Eleanore Webster (located in Series I Armistead Churchill Gordon, Jr., general correspondence of Cornelia Gordon Box: 2 Folder: 6) There is a letter from Cornelia to Mrs. Eleanor Webster (Harry's mother) alluding to Ann's miscarriage.] (Box 18)
  - 1954 Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 42 items (Box-folder 18:2)
    Cornelia wrote about a variety of current topics such as Joseph McCarthy; the Supreme Court decision to end segregation; eleven students were expelled by President Darden; Walt Harding was not being kept on at UVA; James Southall Wilson was to teach at Hollins; and new evidence for how harmful it was to smoke. Cornelia took a job at Monticello as a tour guide; and Ann was pregnant with Liza. Armistead died in 1953 (but the circumstances were not mentioned, probably heart attack) she wrote about not having any purpose in life without him and that Atcheson and Virginia Hench were her best friends.
  - 1955 January-April Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 29 items (Box-folder 18:3)
    Cornelia wrote about Nell Lewis and that her brother, Dr. Ivey Lewis was considered by the faculty to be a "nit wit." There is also an editorial by Nancy Hale Bowers(March 9, 1955) about desegregation and Nell Lewis. Cornelia wrote about a new broadcast (and LP) by Reuben Ship that was a satire on Joseph McCarthy and was very popular in the United States and Britain. Cornelia mentioned Phil Williams' suicide, and that Archie Hill was leaving to teach in Texas.
  - 1955 May-December Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 33 items (Box-folder 18:4)
    Cornelia mentioned the deaths of Jerry Ann Kean, and Lillian Dabney (Mrs. Archie Dabney).
  - 1956-1957 Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 13 items (Box-folder 18:5)
    Cornelia took in students and wrote a colorful description of her student boarder. She also wrote that the Geldards were going to England for work with the Navy. There is a letter from Harry Clemons praising the Gordon family (starting with General William Fitzhugh Gordon to George Loyall Gordon, to Rector Armistead Churchill Gordon, Sr. to Armistead Churchill Gordon, Jr.) for their contributions to the University of Virginia. The UVA Library purchased a collection of rare books in honor of the memory of Armistead Churchill Gordon, Jr. and Cornelia sent the letter to Ann. Harry and Ann had their third child, Armistead Webster "Oppit."
  - 1960-1961 Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 22 items (Box-folder 18:6)
    Ann and Harry had a fourth child, Maggie (1959). There is a news clipping about an eclipse; their next tour in Rhodesia, South Africa; and news clippings about Africa.
  - 1964 January-April Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 23 items (Box-folder 18:7)
    Cornelia travelled to New Orleans and Mexico. Armistead's brother, James Gordon was very ill with a brain tumor and had an operation. Nannie Saunders died,and Frank Geldard had surgery for prostrate trouble. Cornelia included news clippings about Africa in many of her letters during this period.
  - 1964 May-December Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 25 items (Box-folder 19:1)
    The Webster family returned to Washington D. C. William (Barney) Webster attended Groton. Cornelia retired from working at Monticello. Cornelia wrote that the portrait of James Southall Wilson was "dreadful." She also mentioned the retirements of James Kindred and Carl Speidel; and the divorce of Laura Speed Elliot and Bill Brown, a school friend of Ann's. There is a news clipping about the death of UVA librarian, Louise Savage.
  - 1965 January-June Correspondence Cornelia Gordon to Ann Webster, 23 items (Box-folder 19:2)
    Cornelia travelled to Florida. She wrote about her long friendship with James Southall Wilson which went back to when Armistead was a student at William and Mary and Wilson was a teacher there. She also included more news clippings about Africa.
  - 1965 July-December Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 15 items (Box-folder 19:3)
    Cornelia wrote that Mrs. Bessie Walker died (in the Seven Society). There are news clippings about a grant to the University of Virginia from the National Science Foundation. Also included is biographical information about Francis Pickens Miller.
  - 1966 January-July Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 23 items (Box-folder 19:4)
  - 1966 August-December Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 29 items (Box-folder 19:5)
    Cornelia wrote that Frank Geldard was to be best man in Raymond Bice's wedding, and that Dr. Henry B. Mulholland died. There is a news clipping that Edward Younger was named Dean of the Graduate School of Arts and Sciences.
  - 1967 January-June Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 40 items (Box-folder 19:6)
    There is news clipping about a bomb threat at Cabell Hall. The Webster's were in their next assignment in The Hague, The Netherlands.
  - 1968 Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 44 items (Box-folder 19:7)
    There is a news clipping from the Daily Progress about a Charlottesville woman, named Anna Anderson who claimed to be Anastasia Romanov. There is also a letter from Ann Webster to Caroline Conant who was visiting the Websters at the same time as Cornelia.
  - 1969 Correspondence between Ann Webster family and Cornelia Gordon, 39 items (Box-folder 19:8)
    There are more news clippings about Anna Anderson and her marriage to University of Virginia History Professor, John E. Manahan. Cornelia mentioned that Atcheson Hench attended the student rallies for more pay for UVA employees and racial equality. There is also a news clipping about Dr. Oron J. Hale, professor of history being awarded the Commander's Cross of the Order of Merit of the German Federal Republic. Cornelia also wrote that the train carrying Eisenhower to his funeral stopped in Charlottesville and about a "revolutionary movement" in colleges. It is also mentioned that James Lindsay Gordon, Armistead's brother, died; and that Armistead's sister, Mary Gordon was being cared for by friends.
    [There are no more letters because Cornelia Gordon died from sleeping pills in September 1969].
  - 1936-1940 Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 29 items (Box-folder 20:1)
    Letters between Ann Gordon and her friends including Peggy Macleod and Margaret Hench
  - 1941-1942 Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 16 items (Box-folder 20:2)
  - 1943n.d. Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 29 items (Box-folder 20:3)
  - 1944 January-May Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 23 items (Box-folder 20:4)
  - 1944 June-December Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 34 items (Box-folder 20:5)
  - 1945 January-June Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 21 items (Box-folder 20:6)
  - 1945 July-December Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 36 items (Box-folder 20:7)
  - 1945n. d. Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 17 items (Box-folder 20:8)
  - 1946 January-March Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 26 items (Box-folder 21:1)
  - 1946 April-May Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 17 items (Box-folder 21:2)
  - 1946 June-July Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 19 items (Box-folder 21:3)
    Correspondents of Ann's (while she was attending St. Anne's during the year and living with her parents in Washington D. C. in the summer) include Jeannette Atkins; Martha "Martee" Chanutin; Constance "Connie" Adams Stoney; Dillon; Mary Louise Frey; Gordon "Mac" Morrison; Peggy Macleod and Margaret "Margie" Hench.
  - 1946 August-September Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 36 items (Box-folder 21:4)
    There is correspondence from friends while Ann was at home in the summer and at Wellesley College in the fall. Correspondents include Peggy Macleod; Margaret Hench; Connie Stoney; Veneesh Fawcus;]Gigi MacKnight; Lois Ann Lehman; Pat Bancroft; Cadet George Mason; Ellen Underwood; Gordon Morrison; Hugh Weedon; [Dillon;] and William "Regis" Chauvenet.
  - 1946 October-December Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 45 items (Box-folder 21:5)
    Correspondents include Margaret Hench; Derwood Chase, Jr.; Gigi MacKnight, William "Regis" Chaubenet; Hugh Weedon; Zachary Morfogen; Gordon Morrison; Martha "Martee" Chanutin; Randy Neal; Art; Jean; Brady; Johnathon; Sallie Merritt; Johnnie Welch; and Cadet George Mason.
  - 1947 January-Marchn. d. Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 44 items (Box-folder 21:6)
    Correspondents of Ann's while at Wellesley include [Moo; ][Appie;] [Coleman; ][Yankee; ]William "Regis" Chauvenet; Ellen Underwood; [Brady;] Jeanette and Marie Louise Frey; [Jean;] Peggy Macleod; Gigi Macknight; Peter S. Mansfield; [Van;] Donald J. Sterling, Jr.; Gordon Morrison; Charles Makepeace; J. H. Call; and [Newt;].
  - 1947 April-June Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 31 items (Box-folder 21:7)
    Correspondents of Ann's while at Wellesley include Pat Bancroft; Peggy Macleod; Martha "Martee" Chanutin; [Barber;] [Claire;] Donald J. Sterling, Jr.; William "Regis" Chauvenet; Margaret Hench; [Rick; ]William and Eleanore Webster; Gigi MacKnight; Cadet George Mason; [Jean;]Grace A. Fletcher; and Abbot Fletcher
  - 1947 July-Decembern. d. Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 42 items (Box-folder 22:1)
    Correspondents of Ann's while at Wellesley include Donald J. Sterling, Jr.; Pat Bancroft; Abbot Fletcher; and Hugh Weedon. There is also a letter from Ann to William Spencer.
  - 1948 Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 44 items (Box-folder 22:2)
    Correspondents of Ann while she was at Wellesley include Donald J. Sterling, Jr.; Mary Louise Frey; Sallie Merritt; Lieutenant John Ordway; [Dillon; ]Jeannette Atkins; Gordon Morrison; Cadet George Mason; and Abbot Fletcher.
  - n. d. Ann Gordon correspondence with her school friends, 17 items (Box-folder 22:3)
  - 1933-1937 Ann Gordon creative work, 37 items (Box-folder 22:4)
    Collection of stories, poems, and art work by Ann Gordon
  - 1940 Ann Gordon journal (Box-folder 22:5)
    one bound diary
  - 1942 Ann Gordon journal, 1 notebook (Box-folder 22:6)
    Ann was boarding at St. Anne's School and wrote about her friends and school. There are also a couple of stories by Ann, including a girl being raped by a German soldier.
  - 1942-1943 Ann Gordon journals, 2 items (Box-folder 22:7)
    There are small pages of poems; an autograph book; 2 bound diaries; and three date books.
  - 1942-1956 Ann Gordon journals, 7 items (Box-folder 23:1)
  - 1946 Ann Gordon journal, 1 item (Box-folder 23:2)
    There are loose pages from a notebook about her first dates with Harry, and Charles Makepeace.
  - 1950's Ann Gordon journal, 1 item (Box-folder 23:3)
    There is a notebook on expenses.
  - 1962 Ann Gordon journal, 1 item (Box-folder 23:4)